Francisco Pérez Hernández

Mexico City, Mexico 🗷 devfcph@gmail.com 🛘 9613723412 🛅 in/cris-hernandez-fcphdev 🛥 main--devfcph.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic Software Developer with 5+ years of work experience in IT. I consider myself a person with logical and critical thinking, analytical and focused on problem solving.

I have a passion for the challenges that are presented to me every day, since each one of them is an opportunity to test my skills, qualities and experience as a programmer.

EXPERIENCE

Microservices Developer | Grupo Salinas | México · Hybrid | October 2022 - Presentj

- Developed and maintained microservices that were built with Java, increased performance by 10%, and reduced latency across microservices by 15% to improve user experience.
- Utilized Docker and GitLab to create and maintain container-based microservices, providing standardized and secure deployments.

iOS frontend mobile | GoNet An Orion Innovation Company | México · Remote | July 2022 - October 2022

- Designed user interfaces for iOS applications using Swift
- Skills: Swfit, REST

Fullstack Developer | GOBIERNO DEL ESTADO DE CHIAPAS/SECRETARIA DE HACIENDA | Tuxtla Gutiérrez, Chiapas, México | October 2020 - October 2022

- Developed web applications using Microsoft SQL Server, ASP.NET Web API and Vue.js
- Implemented agile software development methodology and used Scrum to maintain development progress. .
- Developed intuitive and user-friendly interfaces that increased user engagement.

Fullstack Developer | Global Transfer MX | Tuxtla Gutiérrez, Chiapas, México | June 2020 - September 2020

- Skills: RESTful WebServices Flutter Laravel Microsoft SQL Server PHP
- Developed web services with RESTful architecture, using Laravel PHP framework and Microsoft SQL Server for storage.

Fullstack Developer | INDUXSOFT DATA SERVICES S DE RL DE CV | Tuxtla Gutiérrez, Chiapas, México | August 2018 - January 2020

- Developed client-server applications with the help of various technologies including JQuery, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C#.
- Implemented and tested a number of solutions resolving complex data issues while ensuring the robustness and scalability of the code.

EDUCATION

Software Development and Technology Engineering | Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas | July 2022

• Main topics: [] Object Oriented Programming [OOP] [] Structured programming [] Database Management [] SOAP & REST services [] Robotics & Al [] Project management [] Web Anns

Exchange Student | Universidad de Boyacá | June 2020

I got a scholarship to study in Boyacá, Colombia.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Educate Machine Learning Foundations | Amazon Web Services (AWS) | 2023

Cloud Architecture | Google Cloud Skills Boost | 2023

Cloud Engineering | Google Cloud Skills Boost | 2023

Google Cloud Essentials | Google Cloud Skills Boost | 2023

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) | SCRUMstudy - Accreditation Body for Scrum and Agile | 2022

SKILLS

Industry Knowledge: Cloud Computing, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning, Apache Kafka, ASP.NET Web API, Frameworks de PHP, Desarrollo web, Desarrollo Full Stack

Tools & Technologies: AWS, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Google Cloud, Oracle Database, Gestión de APIs Apigee, Swift (lenguaje de programación), Bootstrap, MySQL, RESTful WebServices, Flutter, Laravel, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, NET Framework, PHP, JavaScript, C#, Git, Vue.js

Languages: English B1